<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>christopher himes</title>
    <description>Christopher Himes is a Product Owner living in Metro Detroit.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 15:26:39 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 15:26:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.4.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Job Search Personality Test</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the job search and coaching I’ve taken a personality test offered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextjobtraining.com/&quot;&gt;NextJob&lt;/a&gt;. Posted below are the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;gold-backup-blue-introvert&quot;&gt;Gold Backup Blue Introvert&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;overall&quot;&gt;Overall&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realistic, grounded and practical, you are one of the pillars of your community and seen by others as able to get the job done. Gold/Blues honor “the system”, trust contracts and organize life and work around procedures. Your colleagues and family members all feel secure and stable under your watch - as long as they measure up to your high standards. You can, however, be the classic “Type A” personality, demanding much of others both at home and work. But those demands are never made capriciously; you think things through and always are cautious about changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With your highly developed management skills, duty-bound work ethic and ability to concentrate, you rise to top-level positions wherever you invest your efforts. Fierce loyalty to your company cements your status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When undertaking a task, you bring to it logic, impersonal analysis, common sense and practical experience. Golds gravitate to situations where you have to plan ahead, set goals and control the schedule. Highly observant of details, you are gifted at implementing well-defined policies and ensuring that things remain orderly and on track. While reserved, you communicate in a style that is clear and direct and are seen as fair and consistent when dealing with others. You honor traditions and rituals, observing holidays, religious and cultural events with appropriate fanfare. For you, these times are important symbols of continuity to be passed on to the next
generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Appropriateness” is your watchword. Your strong morals lead you to judge others, and speak up if they seem to blur right and wrong. You simply want the world to stay organized and free from the chaos that follows when rules are broken. Even flamboyant dress and unconventional behavior try your tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;natural-strengths&quot;&gt;Natural Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Naturally adapt to the role assigned to you, be it leader or follower&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create and enforce policies, procedures, and schedules that keep everyone on track&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are fair with others and earn their respect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have outstanding logistical skills – i.e. getting the right things, to the right people, in the right amounts, to the right place at the right time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Respect the chain of command&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attend to the practical needs of the organization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are decisive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uphold exacting standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;challenges&quot;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your potential blind spots may include some of the following. 
You:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May prematurely dismiss new ideas. (Dismiss nothing until you investigate.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May see only the flaws in the efforts of others and not give credit where credit is due. (Make it a point of giving some sort of affirmation to colleagues before listing flaws.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on immediate results and overlook long-range implications. (Invest some time in long-range planning and get more comfortable with it as a tool.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are fixed in supporting established ways of doing things. (The tried-and-true contribute much to efficiency. But they won’t keep your company alive when the market is changing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are rigid about how others should perform their responsibilities. (Results are the priority, not necessarily the process of getting there. Respect other methods while awaiting results.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-work-environment&quot;&gt;Best Work Environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be most productive and energized when your work culture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Has clear rules and expectations and a well-defined hierarchy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Includes hard-working and logical co-workers who pride themselves on doing things right.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is a stable and well-respected institution with a predictable future. You work hard and want to be rewarded with money and respect.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rewards dependability and precision. You’re on time, have a well-planned schedule and do your job with consistency. No company runs well for long without a Gold/Blue Introvert&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Involves concrete and practical projects and products. Intangible services are tough for you to quantify and measure. Stick with the things you can touch and see.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is results-oriented. You are skeptical of any work that can’t be evaluated on a spreadsheet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Values loyalty and commitment. In today’s workplace, however, placing your loyalty with a mentor may be better.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows for private space. As an Introvert, your batteries get drained when dealing with people, even if your people skills are superb. You think and perform better in a private space; insist on one as a condition of employment if at all possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;entrepreneurial-style&quot;&gt;Entrepreneurial Style&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;setting-goals&quot;&gt;Setting Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You excel at setting goals and making plans to achieve them. You prioritize, follow through and evaluate progress effortlessly. What you are not good at is modifying your ideas to adapt to changing circumstances. Before casting your business plan in stone, run it by people you respect who are of different from you. Ask them what additional options to consider. Don’t rush into it, even if you are excited and energized. Then, schedule re-evaluations at specific points along the way. Mark your calendar to sit back and reflect whether your goals are being met or you need to readjust them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;at-the-start-of-a-venture&quot;&gt;At the Start of a Venture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are not one of the world’s “dreamers and schemers,” but many Golds have come up with brilliant business ideas and gotten rich from them. At your core, you are driven to be a responsible overseer of people and resources, and this makes you a cautious risk-taker. In your favor, you are not likely to be diverted by other opportunities. You will rely on tried-and-true methodology to move predictably from one milestone to the next.
Once in business, your first priority is establishing order. Systems and procedures are in place virtually from Day One. The sooner you can create predictability in your business, whether in sales, manufactured inventory or cash flow, the more comfortable you are.
Foreseeing and responding to changes in the marketplace will never be your forte, and handling unexpected crises is downright stressful to you. Make sure you have associates on board to handle emergencies and identify future trends and that might impact your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;approach-to-money--compensation&quot;&gt;Approach To Money &amp;amp; Compensation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finances-in-general&quot;&gt;Finances in general&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money is important to your sense of security. You are highly focused on saving and long-term planning, and fully in control of your cash flow at all times. You abhor the misuse of money and rarely go into debt or squander the assets you have. Your investments have to be well researched, backed by a solid track record and fully documented with concrete facts. As long as investments meet these criteria, you’ll invest directly in the market; but mutual funds are a popular option for Golds. You want your portfolio to be your passport to a worry-free future, and you are likely to achieve this goal early in life.
You have a limited tolerance for risk and volatility, favoring time-tested strategies. Fixed income instruments like bonds and GICs make you comfortable along with a portfolio of blue chip stocks. Meanwhile, you prefer working with well-established firms, insisting upon advisors who are organized, consistent and produce predictable results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;compensation--negotiating-style&quot;&gt;Compensation &amp;amp; Negotiating Style&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are a focused and tough negotiator, having researched what you’re worth well in advance. Gold/Blues can be prone to “bag person syndrome” - the fear that you will wind up penniless on the streets. Because you feel your security is on the line, you accept nothing less than everything there is to get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;job-search--your-strengths-and-potential-challenges&quot;&gt;Job Search – Your Strengths and Potential Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an interviewer whose style is close to your own, you will feel immediate rapport. However, if your interviewer is different, use the suggestions in parentheses below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In following your natural interviewing style, you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are calm and composed. (This can look like disinterest – make sure to speak more than you normally do, especially at first.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Present yourself as a capable and competent candidate. (You document your
experience well, in an easy-to-follow manner.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prefer written communications before face-to-face meetings. (Gather facts from all sources.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share few feelings with people. (Interviewers rely on their emotional response to you as a big part of their decision-making process. Prioritize building a personal rapport with such an interviewer by preparing answers to their emotion-based questions. Role play with a friend.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on the present. (Especially if interviewing for a senior level position, you will need to prepare a position on future planning. Research public statements about the company’s future direction prior to an interview.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are patient with the length of the search and the procedures you need to follow. (You’re likely to be the last one standing in a multiple-interview, trial-task type of job screening.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow through with all details; respect deadlines and commitments. (Interviewers respect that you send requested items, call to follow up and send thank-you notes. Your natural career exploration and strategizing strengths allow you to:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be calm and composed in an interview&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on the needs of the present&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide specific information, especially about the steps involved in completing projects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Present your background in a sequential, step-by-step way&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Think before replying&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show confidence in your ability to deal with bottom line issues In order to tone down your potential blind spots, you need to:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cushion your tendency to be abrupt; rehearse some areas of small talk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare questions to ask interviewer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare to talk about yourself on a personal level&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Express enthusiasm and be assertive about selling, not just stating, your accomplishments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do some thinking about a prospective company’s future direction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be willing to consider less obvious career opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here it listed out some possible jobs but I didn’t want to recreate all the formatting so I’ve included a link to it &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/pdf/Personality.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t necessarily agree with all of this but many things rang true which surprised me honestly.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/24/personality-test.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/24/personality-test.html</guid>
        
        <category>Job Search</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Light and Dark</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a fan of dark mode on sites, in development editors, and in the operating system too. Staring at a mostly white screen all day is exhausting and I like the way the content on screen emerges from the darkness with dark mode enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesg.blog/2024/11/24/dark-mode&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; from James G, I set about creating a light mode for this site. This is the reverse from what James had done as he started with a light mode but the the ideas are the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My :root to make this work currently looks like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;:root {
    color-scheme: light dark;
    --dark-background-color: rgb(26, 26, 26);
    --dark-foreground-color: rgb(32, 255, 188);
    --dark-link-color: rgb(25, 209, 255);
    --dark-text-color: rgb(240,240,240);

    --light-background-color: rgb(240,240,240);
    --light-foreground-color: rgb(0, 119, 83);    
    --light-link-color: rgb(1, 151, 189);
    --light-text-color: rgb(26, 26, 26);

    --line-color: rgba(211, 211, 211, 30%);
  }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;color-scheme&lt;/code&gt; term is required to respect the users setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the global variables set it’s just a matter of using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;light-dark()&lt;/code&gt; to set the appropriate colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;p, li, ul {
    color: light-dark(var(--light-text-color), var(--dark-text-color));
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still really prefer the dark mode version of the site, so check that out if you’re interested. It’s just a matter of toggling between light and dark in the browser settings. In Zen browser it’s in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;General &amp;gt; Language and Appearance&lt;/code&gt; which means I don’t even have to scroll in the settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which ever mode you prefer I hope you like what you see.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 14:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/23/light-and-dark.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/23/light-and-dark.html</guid>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
        <category>meta</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Now Update and Todo List</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve updated the &lt;a href=&quot;/now&quot;&gt;now&lt;/a&gt; page following recent events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I have a few items I’ve identified and included in the &lt;a href=&quot;/todo&quot;&gt;todo&lt;/a&gt; list for the site. I don’t believe I’ve linked to this previously so I thought I would do so now.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 17:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/22/now-update-and-todo-list.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/22/now-update-and-todo-list.html</guid>
        
        <category>now</category>
        
        <category>todo</category>
        
        <category>meta</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 12</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s week one of my &lt;a href=&quot;https://12weekyear.com/&quot;&gt;12 Week Year&lt;/a&gt; but it’s the 12th week of the year so I’m calling it week 12. This is meant to be forward looking to a week note for every week of the year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I updated my resume to showcase my experience, skills, and accomplishments as a Product Owner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Signed up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextjobtraining.com/&quot;&gt;NextJob&lt;/a&gt; to take advantage of that benefit from my previous employer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scheduled a meeting with a job coach for next week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/cshimes&quot;&gt;my LinkedIn profile&lt;/a&gt; and added a few people that I previously worked with in the past.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Originally planned to apply to a few jobs this week but have been saving them for next week and a better resume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started documenting some specific projects I’ve had at work over the last few years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set resume/cv to appear in the main navigation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/21/weeknotes-week12.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/21/weeknotes-week12.html</guid>
        
        <category>Week Notes</category>
        
        <category>Week 12</category>
        
        <category>resume</category>
        
        <category>NextJob</category>
        
        <category>Product Owner</category>
        
        <category>Job Search</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 16 years, 9 months and 12 days I’m unemployed. It’s upsetting and scary but also exciting in a way. That’s a long time for anyone to be doing something and it would be nice to do something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Already I’m looking for ways to use my time productively. I’ve always been somewhat dubious about self help books and influencers of that type. However, I have found a few things lately that I’m going to try. Looking to add some structure in the near term but maybe they’ll stick around and become habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like the idea of &lt;a href=&quot;https://doingweeknotes.com/&quot;&gt;Week Notes&lt;/a&gt;, a concept I’ve only been introduced to recently. The general idea is to post publicly (typically within an organization) what your team has worked on this week. Hopefully, making this information public gives other teams, leadership, etc., a better idea of what is going on. This of course is another silo breaking procedure but as activity more akin to a work journal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having sent status emails for years this seems like a nice way to add context to whatever dates may be out there. For example if there is something that comes up unexpectedly this could appear in the weeknote and help avoid future surprises. Of course this is not a replacement for other forms of communication but it may reach people outside of traditional channels. The public forum means not having to guess who should be included on the email chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly than that a team can celebrate a win every week. There are things worth celebrating all the time. Too often focus is on a larger deliverable when so many smaller victories happen every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What does that mean for me though?&lt;/em&gt; I’m going to be working toward my next job every week and documenting these efforts may help me. Having a bit of a self check-in weekly seems valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the rest of the plan I’m starting today. I’m acting with intent over the next 12 weeks implementing a much more casual version of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://12weekyear.com/&quot;&gt;12 Week Year&lt;/a&gt; after watching this &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/5SPjd9Zu4-w?si=rjBU_E7WPI-ww1KC&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; by Zach Highley. I’ve made a few goals and I’m going to keep track of what I’m doing to try and accomplish them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help me keep track of my goals and my planned activities for the 12 weeks I’ve added a template already setup for this sort of thing on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so&quot;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re not famililar with Notion it started as a note taking app like Evernote. But it has turned into a suite of tools for project management, documentation, and collaboration. Random promotion of Notion aside I’ve got the system setup I just need to start the work.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/17/starting-weeknotes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/17/starting-weeknotes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Week Notes</category>
        
        <category>12 Week Year</category>
        
        <category>Notion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Now Page 2024</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While looking at personal sites for inspiration I found the idea of a now page. So I decided to make one for myself. There are lots of examples of this on &lt;a href=&quot;https://nownownow.com&quot;&gt;NowNowNow&lt;/a&gt; but my now page is located at &lt;a href=&quot;/now&quot;&gt;/now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now it includes a personal, movie/TV, and music section. For the music section I’ve added a line about the latest song I listened to on &lt;a href=&quot;https://spotify.com&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://last.fm&quot;&gt;last.fm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a good opportunity to implement api access on the site via a private key. Which is something I understood in practice but had never actually implemented myself. Just not something I had experimented with in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing I did was go to last.fm and get an api key. From there I read the documentation they provided and reviewed samples I found just searching ye olde interweb. Using the most barebone page imaginable to use the key and retrieve the information I was looking for. I have to say there was more trial and error than I thought here which I think is largely due to the type of documentation provided in the api docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, with that done I knew I could pull the information I was looking for and format it as needed. Piecing together the song title, artist, and album of the latest song was complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I needed to move that private key somewhere to actually keep it private. While the test had hard coded the key onto the page it needs to be stored as an environment variable and accessed in a way that does not expose it to a client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily for me, my host of choice &lt;a href=&quot;https://netlify.com&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt; has some good documentation and site configuration to make this easier. There is a section for Environment Variables within the site configuration which allowed me to specify the api key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there I would need a way to access that information at run time versus having the build of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; site pull it into the code of the site. This was achieved by the use of Netlify functions which allow for server side Javascript to be run to access environment variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to this addition there was not much configuration in the setup of this site for the Netlify build. Now there are a few more requirements and I’m not sure if it could go back to GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, my compuslive upgrading has delayed the launch of the page a bit as well as a few of the supporting tools to build the site had some cascading dependency issues tied to updating one piece or another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the api key was setup, kept private in environment variables, accessed via a server side function call, and used to pull song details, I was ready to build the rest of the /now page. I had originally just setup a HTML page but I went ahead and converted it to markdown to utilize the existing templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I had to decide what was even happening now which I kept pretty light as it is just a first pass. I think having the page out there and reviewing it periodically would be a good sanity check from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/12/06/now-2024.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/12/06/now-2024.html</guid>
        
        <category>now</category>
        
        <category>2024</category>
        
        <category>meta</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simple Silly</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided not to figure out an image for this post and see if that helps get it together faster. I’m not happy with how the images I have on previous posts work with the latest layouts so I’m considering dropping them all together. I do think I could pull original sources and have the look less terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent changes on the site have been focusing on un-bootstrapping the site. This is an excuse in part to experiment with flex box and modern CSS in general. I do not have any projects outside of this site that can scratch that itch. So I figured I would expriment with the site at first and then branch into other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading lots of blogs about things to add to personal sites. So I am making a list and will be making chainges and posting more often (he says again).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy with how much simple the site is now. Not having to provide all of bootstrap has significantly reduced the payload for a first draw.The site does not need a bunch of fancy buttons or styling so the critical css file is small. Frankly, it could be smaller still but I’m not great at css let alone optimizing css.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a version of the site that included cards for the blog posts including gradient borders with rounded corners but I decided to scale that way back. I’m not sure about the dashed lines but they work for the moment. I miss cleaner sites so I have been looking at simpler sites for inspiration. There are some fun ideas out there that I plan to incorporate to the site or just as a prompt.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 07:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/11/21/simple-silly.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/11/21/simple-silly.html</guid>
        
        <category>meta</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lighthouse</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/img/blog/lighthouse/lighthouse.webp&quot; alt=&quot;image of a lighthouse&quot; title=&quot;Lighthouse at night with lots of stars and the light from the house shining bright.&quot; class=&quot;main-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is not big, but it is faster, and more accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the briefest of lead ins to this project I wanted to learn about modern approaches to speed and accessibility. I’ve spent some time on Mastodon and follow a number of people that post about these topics regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want this site to function as fast as it can and be accessible to folks who may not be interacting with it the same way I am. With that as a goal I downloaded the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GoogleChrome/lighthouse&quot;&gt;Lighthouse&lt;/a&gt; extension to analyze this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting off the site looked good for SEO and best practices but had some room for improvement with both performance and accessibility. Thankfully the score for each section comes with specific problems and ways to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For performance images were the largest issue. They have been resized and converted to webp (from jpg). This brought the score up to 100 on desktop but the mobile version only ever got up to 95%. There remains a bit of css that is load blocking and I have not been able to find a way to resolve it without a significant rewrite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as accessibility goes the usual suspects were the culprits. Images lacked alt tags and contrast was too low with some color choices for links. This is relatively easy to resolve. I updated my color choices in CSS to increase contrast. Here too mobile is at 95% and I cannot figure out why. Out of frustration I set the links to white and the background to black and Lighthouse still reported a contrast issue. Anyway I’ve been updating alt tags but I will probably go back and make them a little better when I have time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the final scores!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;desktop&quot;&gt;Desktop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/img/blog/lighthouse/lighthouse-desktop.webp&quot; alt=&quot;desktop score&quot; title=&quot;Lighthouse scores for desktop. Performance is 100%. Accessibility is 100%. Best Practices is 100%. SEO is 100%.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mobile&quot;&gt;Mobile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/img/blog/lighthouse/lighthouse-mobile.webp&quot; alt=&quot;mobile score&quot; title=&quot;Lighthouse scores for mobile. Performance is 95%. Accessibility is 95%. Best Practices is 100%. SEO is 100%.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy to have these scores as high as they are but I do not think this is over just yet. Having read a bunch of ways to improve things, now I want to go further. 95% is pretty good on mobile for performance and accessibility but is there any reason why these cannot be 100% as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rewrite I mentioned earlier is incoming. This site is simply more complicated than it needs to be and I really want to experiment with critical CSS being inlined to prevent load blocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no reason that this site should be a recolor of an existing theme. Especially when that theme is introducing so much unnecessary overhead. Anyway, more on that to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The image above is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@nathjennings_&quot;&gt;Photo by Nathan Jennings on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/07/26/lighthouse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/07/26/lighthouse.html</guid>
        
        <category>lighthouse</category>
        
        <category>SEO</category>
        
        <category>Web Development</category>
        
        <category>Accessibility</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I got married!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/img/blog/i-got-married/married.webp&quot; alt=&quot;main-image&quot; title=&quot;Married&quot; class=&quot;main-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a little over a month now since I got married.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all the planning had been going on for a few years and I’m happy to say everything went really well. We benefitted greatly by having the entire event in one location. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thewhitney.com/&quot;&gt;The Whitney&lt;/a&gt; is a really nice venue with an outdoor location for the ceremony and delicious food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We managed to find lots of great inspiration on Pinterest and vendors on Etsy. There are threats at the moment that Etsy is going in a bad direction but we’ve been very happy with the vendors we found. We spent way too long considering invitations but managed to pick out just about everything else very quickly. It was really nice to know that when planning something my wife and I were so in sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a first look in the library with just us and her son.The ceremony was in the garden where the weather was warm for May but sunny. It was late enough in the year that everything was green and some flowers had bloomed. It was a small ceremony and dinner with just close family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos took a long time but we’re really happy with the result. I’ve updated my socials with a solo image from the day which I like quite a bit. We’ve got a book being printed and we are going to pick out at least one image to frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the wedding we stayed downtown at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedetroitclub.com/&quot;&gt;The Detroit Club&lt;/a&gt; which was a bit fancy but the stay was relaxing. We were within walking distance of a Starbucks and we booked a spa day. The Movement festival was happening downtown so when we rode the People Mover there were some interesting folks making their way around town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The image above is from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://leahandchristopherhimes.com&quot;&gt;wedding site&lt;/a&gt; I made but never showed to anyone but my wife.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/07/11/i-got-married.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/07/11/i-got-married.html</guid>
        
        <category>married</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Add Comments</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/img/blog/add-comments/comments.webp&quot; alt=&quot;main-image&quot; title=&quot;Comments&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My blog has &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinmastodon.org/&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; powered comments now and this post is really just a test for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is almost completely the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cassidyjames.com/blog/fediverse-blog-comments-mastodon/&quot;&gt;Cassidy James&lt;/a&gt; implementation of comments via Mastodon. Although I do have plans to do some more specific styling for this site it works well as is. Don’t have much more to say about it other than thanks to Mr. James and if you’re interested in adding Mastodon comments to your site I’ve linked to Cassidy’s post about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may go back and add comments to previous posts but for now this post will be the only one with comments. The implementation requires an API call with reference to an existing post on Mastodon and I’m not sure if I want to be posting about previous entries in this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The image above is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@ninjason&quot;&gt;Photo by Jason Leung on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/01/13/add-comments.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/01/13/add-comments.html</guid>
        
        <category>comments</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
