<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>christopher himes</title>
    <description>Christopher Himes is a Product Owner living in Metro Detroit.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:34:44 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:34:44 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.4.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lighthouse Revisited</title>
        <description>&lt;style&gt;
.box {
  float: left;
  /* height: 50px; */
  /* width: 50px; */
  padding: 15px;
  text-align: center;
  vertical-align: center;
  margin-bottom: 15px;
  border: 1px solid light-dark(rgb(26, 26, 26), rgb(240,240,240));
  color: black;
  /* clear: both; */
}
.white {background-color: rgb(240,240,240);}
.black {background-color: rgb(26, 26, 26);color:white;}
.medium-green {background-color: rgb(0, 87, 59);}
.bright-green {background-color: rgb(32, 255, 188);}
.medium-blue {background-color: rgb(1, 85, 106);}
.bright-blue {background-color: rgb(25, 209, 255);}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing about this site that I’m not happy with is I don’t have the necessary tests in place to ensure changes meet the standard of quality I want. Case in point, a &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2024/07/26/lighthouse&quot;&gt;few months back&lt;/a&gt; I got the site to a good &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GoogleChrome/lighthouse&quot;&gt;lighthouse&lt;/a&gt; score. Not just good, the site was at 100% for performance, accessibility, best practices, and SEO on desktop. Mobile had 95% for performance and accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;desktop-original&quot;&gt;Desktop (original)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blogimg&quot; alt=&quot;Past lighthouse scores of 100% in all categories&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/assets/img//blog/lighthouse/lighthouse-desktop.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mobile-original&quot;&gt;Mobile (original)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blogimg&quot; alt=&quot;Past lighthouse scores of 100% in all categories but performance and accessibility at 95%&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/assets/img//blog/lighthouse/lighthouse-mobile.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had not rerun the lighthouse test in a while. The recent run was not good as pictured below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blogimg&quot; alt=&quot;Recent light mode scores with 87% for performance, 95% for accessibility, and 100% for best practices and SEO&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/assets/img//blog/lighthouse-revisited/lighthouse-score-current.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing that jumps out, and maybe it’s because it’s in &lt;span style=&quot;color:red&quot;&gt;red&lt;/span&gt;, is the “Largest Contentful Paint element”. My face apparently is just too big. To address this I resized the image to match the dimension it will be displayed. Just to be sure I introduced a little bit of lossy compression using cwebp in the command line. Not enough that you should notice but just enough to reduce the file size a little more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cwebp -q 85 new-face-325x325.webp -o home-face-325x325.webp
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there I got a lower score than before with the report saying the image was low resolution and it was expecting something around 488 pixels square. I ended up resolving this issue by starting over and providing an image of 650x650 for the 325x325 square. This appears to be a requirement for serving to higher density screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I did find interesting is that it appears lighthouse is using the light mode as a default. This of course exposes that I did not do enough testing of &lt;a href=&quot;https://dequeuniversity.com/rules/axe/4.10/color-contrast&quot;&gt;color contrast&lt;/a&gt; when setting up the &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2025/04/16/light-and-dark-revisited&quot;&gt;light mode&lt;/a&gt;. Based on the feedback from the contrast test I’ve updated the light mode to the following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;box white&quot;&gt;rgb(240,240,240)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box medium-green&quot;&gt;rgb(0, 87, 59)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box medium-blue&quot;&gt;rgb(1, 85, 106)&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blogimg&quot; alt=&quot;Home page in the latest version of light mode with slightly darker blue and green&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/assets/img//blog/lighthouse-revisited/light-mode-updated.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may expect the dark mode which existed first and was used in the original test meets the contrast requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more thing I did was to shift some css styling to a sheet that is loaded asynchronously versus the inline critical styling. This has been a bit of guess and check on my part and I’m not sure I have everything where it needs to be just yet. If you see any jumps or restyling when a page loads please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing slowing down the site was font awesome icons for email, mastodon, bluesky, RSS feed, and github. I tried a few different ways to speed this up but ultimately went with doing away with the icons altogether. For now it’s kinda nice not having a company’s logo on my site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked through the mobile score first as this is usually the most difficult to get right. The standards are understandably higher due to the variety of devices and connections. The main issue here was the picture of my face which was either too large of a file or low resolution. These things seem like opposites but there is a balancing act between quality images and file size. Ultimately I ended up recreating the image from its source and working with the compression of cwebp to get to a high enough quality image while having a low load time in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the results of these efforts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;desktop&quot;&gt;Desktop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blogimg&quot; alt=&quot;Desktop Lighthouse score results with all four categories listed at 100%&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/assets/img//blog/lighthouse-revisited/lighthouse-desktop.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mobile&quot;&gt;Mobile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blogimg&quot; alt=&quot;Mobile Lighthouse score results with all four categories listed at 100%&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/assets/img//blog/lighthouse-revisited/lighthouse-mobile.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bit of trial and error both the mobile and desktop versions of the site have 100% for all four categories! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some optional items on the lighthouse page that I would like to pursue as well so this will likely get revisited again. For now things are faster and more people can interact comfortably with the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is day 11 of #100DaysToOffload.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/29/lighthouse-revisited.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/29/lighthouse-revisited.html</guid>
        
        <category>Meta</category>
        
        <category>100 Days To Offload</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Read Time and Tags</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having dramatically scaled back this site to make the restyling easier I have been slowly adding back in some removed features. One thing I’ve wanted to enable for a while is making a posts tags visible. I have continued to add tags to posts as they’re going out but that extra bit of information has not been shared anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’ve added to each post on the blog page so anyone visiting the site can see how a post is tagged when deciding whether or not to click into read the whole article. These also appear again once you’ve clicked through to the full post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are the current light and dark mode versions of the current stylings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blogimg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of the dark version of the Meta and 100 Days to Offload tags associated with this blog post&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/assets/img//blog/read-time-and-tags/tag-dark.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blogimg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of the dark version of the Meta and 100 Days to Offload tags associated with this blog post&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/assets/img//blog/read-time-and-tags/tag-light.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tags are styled as buttons which when clicked take you to the tag index page. Initially I had the tags slugified&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; which didn’t take you to the correct part of the page. This has been removed so each link has a # and should navigate you to the part of the tag index page with similar posts. I am also adding a feature to the &lt;a href=&quot;/todo&quot;&gt;todo&lt;/a&gt; page for related posts using this tagging. As more posts are added the opportunities to link between posts and filter for specific types of posts increases. I think there will be more to come there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another feature I’ve added to the site is a read time calculator. The site is using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mslinn/jekyll_reading_time&quot;&gt;jekyll_reading_time&lt;/a&gt; gem to calculate the average read time of each post. For now I’ve included this information with each post blurb on the blog page as well as at the top of each post. Adding this feature has really highlighted for me that I mostly post short form blog posts. Essentially, each of these could could have just been a tweet/toot (Xitter/Mastodon). The current longest post is about 8 minutes in read time and it’s the &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2025/03/24/personality-test&quot;&gt;personality test results&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know that I want to be writing novels or anything but I do want to dig into some things more. Thinking that an average of five minutes would be a good amount of time to aim for. That of course is an arbitrary metric and not something I would force. I tend to be overly succinct in my writing so I’ll be working on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are things I’ve liked from other sites I’ve visited and decided to incorporate here. I’m not sure if I like the styling of the tags but that is fairly easy to change. I don’t know if I like the linking or the format of the &lt;a href=&quot;/tags&quot;&gt;tag index page&lt;/a&gt; either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, as with everything else around here it’s a work in progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is day 10 of #100DaysToOffload.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;A slug refers to human readable and URL friendly text like the format of the URL for this post. Often this involves replacing spaces with dashes and removing special characters. The term is carried over from the print world. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/26/read-time-and-tags.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/26/read-time-and-tags.html</guid>
        
        <category>Meta</category>
        
        <category>100 Days To Offload</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 17</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applied to some jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corrected the deprecated warning in the SASS for the @import command used for comments on this site. Switched to @use.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weather ☀️ has been nice so I’ve been working in the yard. The garden beds need some serious care so I’m getting them cleaned up and ready for planting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Had a call about what I’m looking for at a potential employer. Conversation was good but they do not currently have an open position for what I’m looking for. It was nice to talk about my experience either way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Completed the capstone project for the Product Owner IBM certification on Coursera. I don’t usually post to LinkedIn but I did this time. Nice to celebrate a win.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Today was my wife’s late mom’s birthday, so we went to the cemetery to honor her and place some flowers. The irises we planted last year are looking good which is nice. 💐&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is day 9 of #100DaysToOffload.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 12:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/25/weeknotes-week17.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/25/weeknotes-week17.html</guid>
        
        <category>Week Notes</category>
        
        <category>Week 17</category>
        
        <category>100 Days To Offload</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Product Owner Certification</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Currently between roles and one thing I knew immediately that I wanted to do with the extra time was get a certification. I’ve always been doing more informal self improvement and learning but now seemed like a good time to have a little something to show for it and make it a bit more official.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I jumped into some Product Owner courses on Coursera. This track had seven classes with a few projects that were graded. I did learn a few new strategies for prioritization and negotiation which I plan to discuss over the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I miss having a team that is building something together but that will come in time. For now I’m bettering myself both because I want to and because it will help with whatever the next thing is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blogimg&quot; alt=&quot;IBM Product Owner Certification&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/assets/img//blog/ibm-product-owner-certification/cert.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is day 8 of #100DaysToOffload.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/24/ibm-product-owner-certification.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/24/ibm-product-owner-certification.html</guid>
        
        <category>Product Owner</category>
        
        <category>Certification</category>
        
        <category>100 Days To Offload</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 16</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Made even more changes to the resume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Met with the job coach.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applied to some jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scheduled a call for next week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Published a few blog posts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Installed &lt;a href=&quot;https://ohmyz.sh/&quot;&gt;OhMyZSH&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Completed a few lessons on Coursera and started the final project for the IBM Product Owner course.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remained stuck on Cicada Detroit puzzle 20.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Went to Hamtramck with my mom and Josie. Where we got baked goods for Easter from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newpalacebakery.com/&quot;&gt;New Palace Bakery&lt;/a&gt; and had lunch at &lt;a href=&quot;https://polonia-restaurant.net/&quot;&gt;Polonia&lt;/a&gt;. Classic Easter preparation stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drove my wife around on Friday while her car was in the shop again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Completed &lt;a href=&quot;https://overwatch.blizzard.com&quot;&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/a&gt; drives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is day 7 of #100DaysToOffload.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/19/weeknotes-week16.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/19/weeknotes-week16.html</guid>
        
        <category>Week Notes</category>
        
        <category>Week 16</category>
        
        <category>Cicada Detroit</category>
        
        <category>Overwatch 2</category>
        
        <category>100 Days To Offload</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Light and Dark Mode Revisited</title>
        <description>&lt;style&gt;
.box {
  float: left;
  /* height: 50px; */
  /* width: 50px; */
  padding: 15px;
  text-align: center;
  vertical-align: center;
  margin-bottom: 15px;
  border: 1px solid light-dark(rgb(26, 26, 26), rgb(240,240,240));
  color: black;
  /* clear: both; */
}
.white {background-color: rgb(240,240,240);}
.black {background-color: rgb(26, 26, 26);color:white;}
.medium-green {background-color: rgb(0, 119, 83);}
.bright-green {background-color: rgb(32, 255, 188);}
.medium-blue {background-color: rgb(1, 151, 189);}
.bright-blue {background-color: rgb(25, 209, 255);}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to revisit the light and dark update as the original described some changes but didn’t display how these changes impacted the experience on the site. Now that images are working a bit better I figured I would show exactly what’s happening on the site in its current state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dark mode which is the primary way I view the site uses an almost black background with bright green and blue for the headers and links respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;box black&quot;&gt;rgb(26, 26, 26)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box bright-green&quot;&gt;rgb(32, 255, 188)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box bright-blue&quot;&gt;rgb(25, 209, 255)&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blogimg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark mode version of this site with a near black background, bright blue links, white text, and bright green header text&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/assets/img//blog/light-and-dark/dark-mode.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The light mode which I imagine will be the way most people view the site uses an almost white background with medium green and blue for the headers and links respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;box white&quot;&gt;rgb(240,240,240)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box medium-green&quot;&gt;rgb(0, 119, 83)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;box medium-blue&quot;&gt;rgb(1, 151, 189)&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blogimg&quot; alt=&quot;Light mode version of this site with a near white background, medium blue links, near black text, and medium green header text&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/assets/img//blog/light-and-dark/light-mode.webp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I’ve simplified the setup for light and dark based on a recent blog by &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesg.blog/2025/04/03/light-dark-root&quot;&gt;James G&lt;/a&gt; that was a follow up to his original post that inspired this setup in the first place. Previously the CSS suffered from the same redundancy he discussed in his blog post where every time a color was used it checked light-dark. Now this is baked into the :root variables like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;:root {
    color-scheme: light dark;
    --background-color: light-dark(rgb(240,240,240), rgb(26, 26, 26));
    --foreground-color: light-dark(rgb(0, 119, 83), rgb(32, 255, 188));
    --link-color: light-dark(rgb(1, 151, 189), rgb(25, 209, 255));
    --text-color: light-dark(rgb(26, 26, 26), rgb(240,240,240));
    --line-color: rgba(211, 211, 211, 30%);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows h1 to be styled like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;h1 {
    color: var(--foreground-color);
} 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last thing is the use of gradients which also change in response to the light or dark settings from the user. One example is the site-tile which is just how my name at the top left on desktop or the top center on mobile is classed. The variables plug in just the same here but the added simplicity really helps the more complex -webkit-gradient lines legibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.site-title {
    font-family: &apos;lato-normal&apos;, Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif;
    font-size: 1.2em;
    background: -webkit-gradient(linear, left top, right bottom, from(var(--foreground-color)), to(var(--link-color)));
    -webkit-background-clip: text;
    background-clip: text;
    -webkit-text-fill-color: transparent;
    text-decoration: none;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These screenshots were taken by me on 4/11/25.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is day 6 of #100DaysToOffload.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 10:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/16/light-and-dark-revisited.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/16/light-and-dark-revisited.html</guid>
        
        <category>CSS</category>
        
        <category>Meta</category>
        
        <category>100 Days To Offload</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Static Site Images</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently reaking this blog post by Kev Quirk about &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevquirk.com/blog/how-i-manage-jekyll-content&quot;&gt;image handling&lt;/a&gt; on his static site which inspired me to spend some time fixing the images on this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My includes are fairly similar to his but I’m passing a class as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
{{=&amp;lt;% %&amp;gt;=}}&amp;lt;img class=&quot;blogimg&quot; alt=&quot;{{include.alt}}&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/assets/img/{{include.src}}&quot; /&amp;gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image line in each post is identical to his handling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
{% include img.html src=&apos;&apos; alt=&apos;&apos; %}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun side note in creating this post I learned that you have to use {% raw %} and {% endraw %} tags so the &lt;a href=&quot;https://heymichellemac.com/jekyll-liquid-tags-code-snippet&quot;&gt;liquid code&lt;/a&gt; wouldn’t run and replace that information. Also, these tags do not stack so you cannot show this code by putting raw/raw/endraw/endraw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this at least partially corrected I’ll be adding images to more posts going forward and revisiting the dark and light mode update with some images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here just because it would be bad form to have a post about images without including an image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;blogimg&quot; alt=&quot;T-Rex roaring in an urban downtown area&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;https://christopherhimes.com/assets/img//blog/static-images/static-dinosaur.webp&quot; /&gt;
Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@yingone?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=unsplash&quot;&gt;Huang Yingone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is day 5 of #100DaysToOffload.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 07:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/16/static-site-images.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/16/static-site-images.html</guid>
        
        <category>Meta</category>
        
        <category>Images</category>
        
        <category>100 Days To Offload</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ActivityWatch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;ActivityWatch is an app that automatically tracks how you spend time on your devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I mentioned in a previous post I found some new people to follow in my RSS reader. One of those people is &lt;a href=&quot;https://joelchrono.xyz&quot;&gt;Joel&lt;/a&gt; who’s feed introduced me to the service &lt;a href=&quot;https://activitywatch.net/&quot;&gt;ActivityWatch&lt;/a&gt;. This is now currently running on my machine so I can see how exactly I’m spending my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My intention for now is simply to use the reporting for self reflection. Not sure if I want to be publishing any stats publicly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is day 4 of #100DaysToOffload.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 13:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/15/activitywatch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/15/activitywatch.html</guid>
        
        <category>ActivityWatch</category>
        
        <category>100 Days To Offload</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Added a Colophon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Added a &lt;a href=&quot;/colophon&quot;&gt;colophon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia lists a colophon as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In publishing, a colophon (/ˈkɒləfən, -fɒn/) is a brief statement containing information about the publication of a book such as an “imprint” (the place of publication, the publisher, and the date of publication).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My intention is to record the site history, technology stack, and other details of the site there. Really though, check that out if you’re interested in what drives this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is day 3 of #100DaysToOffload.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 12:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/15/colophon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/15/colophon.html</guid>
        
        <category>Meta</category>
        
        <category>Colophon</category>
        
        <category>100 Days To Offload</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 15</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Made even more changes to the resume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Met with the job coach.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applied to some jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Position I had an interview for and took assessments last week let me know that they’re taking a pause about 30 minutes before an interview. These things happen, just a bit disappointed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Completed a few lessons on Coursera and last weeks project was confirmed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Had Taco Bell and went to the Bright Eyes and Cursive concert.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finished the first season The Last of Us with my wife.📺&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remained stuck on Cicada Detroit puzzle 20.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heading to the Zap Zone for my nephews birthday party.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is day 2 of #100DaysToOffload.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/12/weeknotes-week15.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/12/weeknotes-week15.html</guid>
        
        <category>Week Notes</category>
        
        <category>Week 15</category>
        
        <category>concert</category>
        
        <category>Bright Eyes</category>
        
        <category>Cursive</category>
        
        <category>Cicada Detroit</category>
        
        <category>100 Days To Offload</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
