<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>christopher himes</title>
    <description>Christopher Himes is a Product Owner living in Metro Detroit.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:00:17 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 12:00:17 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Now Page 2024</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While looking at personal sites for inspiration I found the idea of a now page. So I decided to make one for myself. There are lots of examples of this on &lt;a href=&quot;https://nownownow.com&quot;&gt;NowNowNow&lt;/a&gt; but my now page is located at &lt;a href=&quot;/now&quot;&gt;/now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now it includes a personal, movie/TV, and music section. For the music section I’ve added a line about the latest song I listened to on &lt;a href=&quot;https://spotify.com&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://last.fm&quot;&gt;last.fm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a good opportunity to implement api access on the site via a private key. Which is something I understood in practice but had never actually implemented myself. Just not something I had experimented with in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing I did was go to last.fm and get an api key. From there I read the documentation they provided and reviewed samples I found just searching ye olde interweb. Using the most barebone page imaginable to use the key and retrieve the information I was looking for. I have to say there was more trial and error than I thought here which I think is largely due to the type of documentation provided in the api docs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, with that done I knew I could pull the information I was looking for and format it as needed. Piecing together the song title, artist, and album of the latest song was complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I needed to move that private key somewhere to actually keep it private. While the test had hard coded the key onto the page it needs to be stored as an environment variable and accessed in a way that does not expose it to a client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily for me, my host of choice &lt;a href=&quot;https://netlify.com&quot;&gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt; has some good documentation and site configuration to make this easier. There is a section for Environment Variables within the site configuration which allowed me to specify the api key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there I would need a way to access that information at run time versus having the build of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; site pull it into the code of the site. This was achieved by the use of Netlify functions which allow for server side Javascript to be run to access environment variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to this addition there was not much configuration in the setup of this site for the Netlify build. Now there are a few more requirements and I’m not sure if it could go back to GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, my compuslive upgrading has delayed the launch of the page a bit as well as a few of the supporting tools to build the site had some cascading dependency issues tied to updating one piece or another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the api key was setup, kept private in environment variables, accessed via a server side function call, and used to pull song details, I was ready to build the rest of the /now page. I had originally just setup a HTML page but I went ahead and converted it to markdown to utilize the existing templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I had to decide what was even happening now which I kept pretty light as it is just a first pass. I think having the page out there and reviewing it periodically would be a good sanity check from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/12/06/now-2024.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/12/06/now-2024.html</guid>
        
        <category>now</category>
        
        <category>2024</category>
        
        <category>meta</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simple Silly</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided not to figure out an image for this post and see if that helps get it together faster. I’m not happy with how the images I have on previous posts work with the latest layouts so I’m considering dropping them all together. I do think I could pull original sources and have the look less terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent changes on the site have been focusing on un-bootstrapping the site. This is an excuse in part to experiment with flex box and modern CSS in general. I do not have any projects outside of this site that can scratch that itch. So I figured I would expriment with the site at first and then branch into other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading lots of blogs about things to add to personal sites. So I am making a list and will be making chainges and posting more often (he says again).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy with how much simple the site is now. Not having to provide all of bootstrap has significantly reduced the payload for a first draw.The site does not need a bunch of fancy buttons or styling so the critical css file is small. Frankly, it could be smaller still but I’m not great at css let alone optimizing css.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a version of the site that included cards for the blog posts including gradient borders with rounded corners but I decided to scale that way back. I’m not sure about the dashed lines but they work for the moment. I miss cleaner sites so I have been looking at simpler sites for inspiration. There are some fun ideas out there that I plan to incorporate to the site or just as a prompt.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 07:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/11/21/simple-silly.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/11/21/simple-silly.html</guid>
        
        <category>meta</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lighthouse</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/img/blog/lighthouse/lighthouse.webp&quot; alt=&quot;image of a lighthouse&quot; title=&quot;Lighthouse at night with lots of stars and the light from the house shining bright.&quot; class=&quot;main-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is not big, but it is faster, and more accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the briefest of lead ins to this project I wanted to learn about modern approaches to speed and accessibility. I’ve spent some time on Mastodon and follow a number of people that post about these topics regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want this site to function as fast as it can and be accessible to folks who may not be interacting with it the same way I am. With that as a goal I downloaded the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/GoogleChrome/lighthouse&quot;&gt;Lighthouse&lt;/a&gt; extension to analyze this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting off the site looked good for SEO and best practices but had some room for improvement with both performance and accessibility. Thankfully the score for each section comes with specific problems and ways to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For performance images were the largest issue. They have been resized and converted to webp (from jpg). This brought the score up to 100 on desktop but the mobile version only ever got up to 95%. There remains a bit of css that is load blocking and I have not been able to find a way to resolve it without a significant rewrite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as accessibility goes the usual suspects were the culprits. Images lacked alt tags and contrast was too low with some color choices for links. This is relatively easy to resolve. I updated my color choices in CSS to increase contrast. Here too mobile is at 95% and I cannot figure out why. Out of frustration I set the links to white and the background to black and Lighthouse still reported a contrast issue. Anyway I’ve been updating alt tags but I will probably go back and make them a little better when I have time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the final scores!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;desktop&quot;&gt;Desktop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/img/blog/lighthouse/lighthouse-desktop.webp&quot; alt=&quot;desktop score&quot; title=&quot;Lighthouse scores for desktop. Performance is 100%. Accessibility is 100%. Best Practices is 100%. SEO is 100%.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mobile&quot;&gt;Mobile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/img/blog/lighthouse/lighthouse-mobile.webp&quot; alt=&quot;mobile score&quot; title=&quot;Lighthouse scores for mobile. Performance is 95%. Accessibility is 95%. Best Practices is 100%. SEO is 100%.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy to have these scores as high as they are but I do not think this is over just yet. Having read a bunch of ways to improve things, now I want to go further. 95% is pretty good on mobile for performance and accessibility but is there any reason why these cannot be 100% as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rewrite I mentioned earlier is incoming. This site is simply more complicated than it needs to be and I really want to experiment with critical CSS being inlined to prevent load blocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no reason that this site should be a recolor of an existing theme. Especially when that theme is introducing so much unnecessary overhead. Anyway, more on that to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The image above is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@nathjennings_&quot;&gt;Photo by Nathan Jennings on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 08:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/07/26/lighthouse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/07/26/lighthouse.html</guid>
        
        <category>lighthouse</category>
        
        <category>SEO</category>
        
        <category>Web Development</category>
        
        <category>Accessibility</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I got married!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/img/blog/i-got-married/married.webp&quot; alt=&quot;main-image&quot; title=&quot;Married&quot; class=&quot;main-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a little over a month now since I got married.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all the planning had been going on for a few years and I’m happy to say everything went really well. We benefitted greatly by having the entire event in one location. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thewhitney.com/&quot;&gt;The Whitney&lt;/a&gt; is a really nice venue with an outdoor location for the ceremony and delicious food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We managed to find lots of great inspiration on Pinterest and vendors on Etsy. There are threats at the moment that Etsy is going in a bad direction but we’ve been very happy with the vendors we found. We spent way too long considering invitations but managed to pick out just about everything else very quickly. It was really nice to know that when planning something my wife and I were so in sync.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a first look in the library with just us and her son.The ceremony was in the garden where the weather was warm for May but sunny. It was late enough in the year that everything was green and some flowers had bloomed. It was a small ceremony and dinner with just close family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photos took a long time but we’re really happy with the result. I’ve updated my socials with a solo image from the day which I like quite a bit. We’ve got a book being printed and we are going to pick out at least one image to frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the wedding we stayed downtown at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedetroitclub.com/&quot;&gt;The Detroit Club&lt;/a&gt; which was a bit fancy but the stay was relaxing. We were within walking distance of a Starbucks and we booked a spa day. The Movement festival was happening downtown so when we rode the People Mover there were some interesting folks making their way around town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The image above is from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://leahandchristopherhimes.com&quot;&gt;wedding site&lt;/a&gt; I made but never showed to anyone but my wife.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/07/11/i-got-married.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/07/11/i-got-married.html</guid>
        
        <category>married</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Add Comments</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/img/blog/add-comments/comments.webp&quot; alt=&quot;main-image&quot; title=&quot;Comments&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My blog has &lt;a href=&quot;https://joinmastodon.org/&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; powered comments now and this post is really just a test for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is almost completely the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cassidyjames.com/blog/fediverse-blog-comments-mastodon/&quot;&gt;Cassidy James&lt;/a&gt; implementation of comments via Mastodon. Although I do have plans to do some more specific styling for this site it works well as is. Don’t have much more to say about it other than thanks to Mr. James and if you’re interested in adding Mastodon comments to your site I’ve linked to Cassidy’s post about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may go back and add comments to previous posts but for now this post will be the only one with comments. The implementation requires an API call with reference to an existing post on Mastodon and I’m not sure if I want to be posting about previous entries in this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The image above is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@ninjason&quot;&gt;Photo by Jason Leung on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/01/13/add-comments.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2024/01/13/add-comments.html</guid>
        
        <category>comments</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Stream?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../assets/img/blog/a-stream/stream.webp&quot; alt=&quot;main-image&quot; title=&quot;Stream&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been tinkering around with livestreaming and wanted to document some of the things I found. The experiment has been to stream to both Twitch and YouTube starting with just one or the other and eventually to both at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, lets talk audio. I’ve spent far too much time adjusting the audio for both personal streaming and for work. Current setup utilizes &lt;a href=&quot;https://vb-audio.com&quot;&gt;virtual cables&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsproject.com&quot;&gt;obs&lt;/a&gt; studio filters to achieve what I think is pretty good sounding audio. I’ve primarily been following &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@EposVox&quot;&gt;EposVox&lt;/a&gt; audio quality guides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m using a shock mounted Yeti Blue microphone and passing it throught Noise Suppression using the built in RNNoise method. I haven’t noticed any CPU impact and this works so well. I have the gain on the microphone down very low but I’ve turned the digital gain boosted by 10 dB. This can sound weird without additional filtering but increases my volume without having to be right on top of the microphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next there are a few rounds of correcting for that initial gain boosting and making things sound good. The first round of EQ that uses ReaEQ mostly to cut highs, lows, and a few nasaly places in the mids. This is followed up with a compressor with a 3:1 ratio and a -20dB threshold. From there I do have a Noise Gate set but I’m not sure if it is strictly necessary with all the other things happening. Lastly, there is an additional EQ for some high end and normal speaking range boosting for clarity and to add interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the camera side I have a Razer Kiyo that has most of the default settings but with the white balance manually adjusted. It never quite gets that right and I haven’t found the right filters to counter it consistently. I do typically increase the contrast a little and apply a LUT. This is mostly to add back in some warmth as the default settings can read a bit cold. One thing I wanted to add is that the camera in obs has its own dedicated scene that is then added to other scenes to enable different presentation of the same source. I was running into an issue where changing it on one scene would change it in every scene. This is apparently a known thing about obs but it did cause some confusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baked in streaming setup for OBS is so good it doesn’t typically need to be tweaked. I spent the beter part of the last year streaming exclusively to twitch. This is for a few reasons. First, up until recently it was against twitch’s terms of service to stream to more than one platform. Also, for whatever reason I associate twitch with streaming more than YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been experimenting doing both lately but have determined the only way for me to do that is to use a third party. Specifically, I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;https://restream.io&quot;&gt;Restream&lt;/a&gt; to simultaneously stream to both twitch and YouTube. My upload bandwith is not good so I cannot support both at the same time myself. Setting these up is no more complicated than setting up accounts at each and giving access to Restream. The most complicated piece is setting some of the bitrate and sizing information that will work for both. My current setup is not as good for YouTube as it could be due to the limitations coming from twitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stream infrequently, but when I do it’s at either &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitch.tv/entropygrows/&quot;&gt;EntropyGrows Twitch&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@entropygrows9669&quot;&gt;EntropyGrows YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The image above is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@rzunikoff&quot;&gt;Photo by Raphael Schaller on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/12/29/a-stream.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/12/29/a-stream.html</guid>
        
        <category>streaming</category>
        
        <category>Twitch</category>
        
        <category>YouTube</category>
        
        <category>OBS</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Another New Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../..../../../../assets/img/blog/another-new-design/design.webp&quot; alt=&quot;main-image&quot; title=&quot;Design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a new design, yes it is! This site gets more visual updates than it does blog posts but that’s where we’re at currently. What follows is a brief write up about the decisions that went into reworking the design of this site and what is to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous template for the site used an altered version of a template that I liked but was never quite happy with. This new version takes a similar approach but is way easier to setup and make adjustments. The other piece to consider is that I never really felt comfortable with leading with a blog as I’m not great about keeping up with it obviously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few things about this template and the adjustments I’ve made that I’m happy with. For instance there is significantly less visual clutter on any and every page involved. As I mentioned above I don’t want to lead with a blog so now there is an introductory header element that has my face and a tag line introduction. This is preferable to jumping right into a blog for me. My preference is for dark mode reading so the site reflects that. There is some additional adjustment required to get it where it needs to be but I’m happy with it for now. Additionally I’ve added some brand colors that were lacking in the previous site which was all grey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next approach is to optimize and make it more accessible. I’ve ran lighthouse on it and the plan is to make as many of the suggested changes as possible. One main problem that I agree with and want to correct first is the level of contrast. Some of the colors I’ve chosen and even the standard text are not easy enough to read. I like the way it looks currently but I do hope I’m not the only one that ever looks at the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to follow some tutorials and add comments to my posts. While I don’t suppose I’ll get much in the way of interaction the project to add them using ActivityPub via Mastodon seems interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next projects will be documented and shared here. I’m not a web developer but I do like to poke around with this sort of thing so I’ll be recording that information in a blog in 2023 and beyond. Imagine that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The image above is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@raphaelphotoch&quot;&gt;Photo by Raphael Schaller on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/08/12/another-new-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2023/08/12/another-new-design.html</guid>
        
        <category>site</category>
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>lighthouse</category>
        
        <category>accessibility</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I&apos;m Virtual Now</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../..../../../../assets/img/blog/virtual/virtual.webp&quot; alt=&quot;virtual-image&quot; title=&quot;Virtual&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guess ‘now’ is relative with working at home for the last two years. As of yesterday I no longer have a desk at an office that I could return to when this whole pandemic blows over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a new role, responsibilities, and more people relying on me than I ever have before. This requires me to make fewer explorations into pet projects. In the past I could find some faster way of doing something work related but now I need to delegate that activity to someone else.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
As a Product Owner the daily activities do not typically require much coding so I’m thinking of spending more personal time trying different things out. I downloaded &lt;a href=&quot;https://blender.org&quot;&gt;blender&lt;/a&gt; again and am thinking of playing with some procedural generation. Last week I wrote some &lt;a href=&quot;https://python.org&quot;&gt;python&lt;/a&gt; code to grab some image data so I am thinking about some python projects down the road as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before digging too much into any of that this site’s dependencies are out of control and my plan is to remove them and simplify the entire setup. Not seeing the point in a build process that is broken every time I attempt to build this site. What I mean is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gulpjs.com/&quot;&gt;gulp&lt;/a&gt; setup will be scaled back dramatically and the patchwork of node modules that build this site will be mostly removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The image above is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@sortino&quot;&gt;Joshua Sortino on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/05/14/virtual.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/05/14/virtual.html</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        <category>blender</category>
        
        <category>python</category>
        
        <category>gulp</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Time for a Change</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../../../../../assets/img/blog/time-for-a-change/change.webp&quot; alt=&quot;change-image&quot; title=&quot;change image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The changes to this site now are strictly cosmetic but it is interesting to play with the capabilities of Sass and CSS.  I’ve been unenthusiastic about the previous color scheme for a while so this is a nice brighter setup.
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The image above is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@lemuelbutler&quot;&gt;Lemuel Butler on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 16:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/04/time-for-a-change.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/04/04/time-for-a-change.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Take it Home With You</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../../../../../../../assets/img/blog/take-it-home-with-you/home.webp&quot; alt=&quot;home-image&quot; title=&quot;Home&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next two weeks are going to be exceedingly difficult not to bring work home.  I’m prone to work through things I’m working on at work while I’m at home.  This usually stays to the realm of talking through possible solutions or planning my day or week ahead of time.
&lt;!--more--&gt;
Today, I went as far as signing into Citrix, Trello, and Slack to plan the upcoming week.  We have a fairly aggressive timeline on the current project and I’d prefer to avoid anyone else having to spend time on it outside of work.  I think we can make the timing work we just have to stick to the plan and hopefully do away with any unknowns early in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is the first big project with the new team.  We’ve got everyone up to speed and on the same page, so I forsee a busy but productive week.  I’m excited to demonstrate all of what we can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The image above is from &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/royaannmiller&quot;&gt;Roya Ann Miller on Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 16:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2015/09/13/take-it-home-with-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2015/09/13/take-it-home-with-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        <category>home</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
