<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>christopher himes</title>
    <description>Christopher Himes is a Product Owner living in Metro Detroit.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 13:44:02 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 13:44:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.4.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 15</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Made even more changes to the resume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Met with the job coach.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applied to some jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Position I had an interview for and took assessments last week let me know that they’re taking a pause about 30 minutes before an interview. These things happen, just a bit disappointed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Completed a few lessons on Coursera and last weeks project was confirmed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Had Taco Bell and went to the Bright Eyes and Cursive concert.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finished the first season The Last of Us with my wife.📺&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remained stuck on Cicada Detroit puzzle 20.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is day 2 of #100DaysToOffload.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/12/weeknotes-week14-copy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/12/weeknotes-week14-copy.html</guid>
        
        <category>Week Notes</category>
        
        <category>Week 15</category>
        
        <category>concert</category>
        
        <category>Bright Eyes</category>
        
        <category>Cursive</category>
        
        <category>Cicada Detroit</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>100 Days to Offload</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is day 1 of #100DaysToOffload.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://100daystooffload.com/&quot;&gt;100 Days To Offload&lt;/a&gt; is a challenge to publish 100 posts on your personal blog in a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been trying to write more so I thought this would be a fun challenge. If you go to the website for the challenge they have a hall of fame for people that completed it. This means there are a number of interesting personal blogs to follow as well. Found a few more for the RSS reader.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 07:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/11/100-days-to-offload.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/11/100-days-to-offload.html</guid>
        
        <category>Meta</category>
        
        <category>100 Days To Offload</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adding Pagination</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t remember exactly why I removed the pagination for this site but with the increase of blogs posts I felt that I needed to add it back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After trying and failing to get the standard &lt;em&gt;jekyll-paginate&lt;/em&gt; to work I went ahead and setup &lt;em&gt;jekyll-paginate-v2.&lt;/em&gt; This was easier than some had implied and look now there are multiple pages on this here blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was on the &lt;a href=&quot;/todo&quot;&gt;todo&lt;/a&gt; list so I updated that as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First you must install the gem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install jekyll-paginate-v2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then make sure to update _config.yml. Obviously you don’t need all of these settings but this is what I’m using currently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;plugins:
  - jekyll-paginate-v2

pagination:
  enabled: true
  per_page: 5
  permalink: &apos;/blog/page/:num/&apos;
  title: &apos;:title - page :num&apos;
  limit: 0
  sort_field: &apos;date&apos;
  sort_reverse: true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that did trip me up is I needed to set two permalinks, one for the page itself and another within the pagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;---
layout: page
title: blog
permalink: /blog/
pagination:
  enabled: true
  permalink: /blog/page/:num/
---
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here I added some padding to the pagination and centered it to make sure it was easy to see.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/07/adding-pagination.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/07/adding-pagination.html</guid>
        
        <category>Meta</category>
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
        <category>Pagination</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 14</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Made even more changes to the resume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schedule a meeting with my job coach for next week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;File taxes joinlty for the first time. Pay instead of get a refund for the first time 🥳&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applied to some jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did a test for a position I applied for and have an interview next week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Completed a few lessons on Coursera and have a project pending review.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Had dinner with my brother Matthew at Mexican Village.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watched some Last of Us with my wife.📺&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remained stuck on Cicada Detroit puzzle 20.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cleaned the trap on the dishwasher 🧼.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did some normal laundry (sheets, my clothes, wifes clothes) and some not so normal laundry (chair covers).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swept and mopped all the hard surface floors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vacuumed the carpeted areas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Took down the Christmas Tree  🎄(do not check the date on this post 📆)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Picked up some groceries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Made some chicken noodle soup 🍲.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Found new spots for some things that were on the kitchen counter and coffee table.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Installed &lt;a href=&quot;https://medusajs.com/&quot;&gt;MedusaJS&lt;/a&gt; locally.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Installed MedusaJS on &lt;a href=&quot;https://railway.com/&quot;&gt;Railway&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/04/weeknotes-week14.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/04/04/weeknotes-week14.html</guid>
        
        <category>Week Notes</category>
        
        <category>Week 14</category>
        
        <category>resume</category>
        
        <category>Christmas Tree</category>
        
        <category>Product Owner</category>
        
        <category>Job Search</category>
        
        <category>Soup</category>
        
        <category>Cicada Detroit</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 13</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I made some additional changes to the resume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Met with my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextjobtraining.com/&quot;&gt;NextJob&lt;/a&gt; job coach.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Applied to some jobs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got a call about one of the positions that I applied for and will be following up next week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Had lunch with my mom at Sy Thai.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Did some classes on Coursera.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated the Indeed profile.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enabled a month of LinkedIn Premium.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watched some Last of Us with my wife.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Played Uber driver taking Leah and Noah around town while her car is in the shop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solved the Cicada Detroit puzzle 19 and am immediately stuck on 20.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started taking daily notes in service of writing this post.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed the time stamp in the footer of this page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/29/weeknotes-week13.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/29/weeknotes-week13.html</guid>
        
        <category>Week Notes</category>
        
        <category>Week 13</category>
        
        <category>resume</category>
        
        <category>NextJob</category>
        
        <category>Product Owner</category>
        
        <category>Job Search</category>
        
        <category>coach</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Job Search Personality Test</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of the job search and coaching I’ve taken a personality test offered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextjobtraining.com/&quot;&gt;NextJob&lt;/a&gt;. Posted below are the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;gold-backup-blue-introvert&quot;&gt;Gold Backup Blue Introvert&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;overall&quot;&gt;Overall&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realistic, grounded and practical, you are one of the pillars of your community and seen by others as able to get the job done. Gold/Blues honor “the system”, trust contracts and organize life and work around procedures. Your colleagues and family members all feel secure and stable under your watch - as long as they measure up to your high standards. You can, however, be the classic “Type A” personality, demanding much of others both at home and work. But those demands are never made capriciously; you think things through and always are cautious about changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With your highly developed management skills, duty-bound work ethic and ability to concentrate, you rise to top-level positions wherever you invest your efforts. Fierce loyalty to your company cements your status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When undertaking a task, you bring to it logic, impersonal analysis, common sense and practical experience. Golds gravitate to situations where you have to plan ahead, set goals and control the schedule. Highly observant of details, you are gifted at implementing well-defined policies and ensuring that things remain orderly and on track. While reserved, you communicate in a style that is clear and direct and are seen as fair and consistent when dealing with others. You honor traditions and rituals, observing holidays, religious and cultural events with appropriate fanfare. For you, these times are important symbols of continuity to be passed on to the next
generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Appropriateness” is your watchword. Your strong morals lead you to judge others, and speak up if they seem to blur right and wrong. You simply want the world to stay organized and free from the chaos that follows when rules are broken. Even flamboyant dress and unconventional behavior try your tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;natural-strengths&quot;&gt;Natural Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Naturally adapt to the role assigned to you, be it leader or follower&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create and enforce policies, procedures, and schedules that keep everyone on track&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are fair with others and earn their respect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have outstanding logistical skills – i.e. getting the right things, to the right people, in the right amounts, to the right place at the right time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Respect the chain of command&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Attend to the practical needs of the organization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are decisive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uphold exacting standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;challenges&quot;&gt;Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your potential blind spots may include some of the following. 
You:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May prematurely dismiss new ideas. (Dismiss nothing until you investigate.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May see only the flaws in the efforts of others and not give credit where credit is due. (Make it a point of giving some sort of affirmation to colleagues before listing flaws.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on immediate results and overlook long-range implications. (Invest some time in long-range planning and get more comfortable with it as a tool.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are fixed in supporting established ways of doing things. (The tried-and-true contribute much to efficiency. But they won’t keep your company alive when the market is changing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are rigid about how others should perform their responsibilities. (Results are the priority, not necessarily the process of getting there. Respect other methods while awaiting results.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-work-environment&quot;&gt;Best Work Environment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will be most productive and energized when your work culture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Has clear rules and expectations and a well-defined hierarchy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Includes hard-working and logical co-workers who pride themselves on doing things right.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is a stable and well-respected institution with a predictable future. You work hard and want to be rewarded with money and respect.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rewards dependability and precision. You’re on time, have a well-planned schedule and do your job with consistency. No company runs well for long without a Gold/Blue Introvert&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Involves concrete and practical projects and products. Intangible services are tough for you to quantify and measure. Stick with the things you can touch and see.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is results-oriented. You are skeptical of any work that can’t be evaluated on a spreadsheet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Values loyalty and commitment. In today’s workplace, however, placing your loyalty with a mentor may be better.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allows for private space. As an Introvert, your batteries get drained when dealing with people, even if your people skills are superb. You think and perform better in a private space; insist on one as a condition of employment if at all possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;entrepreneurial-style&quot;&gt;Entrepreneurial Style&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;setting-goals&quot;&gt;Setting Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You excel at setting goals and making plans to achieve them. You prioritize, follow through and evaluate progress effortlessly. What you are not good at is modifying your ideas to adapt to changing circumstances. Before casting your business plan in stone, run it by people you respect who are of different from you. Ask them what additional options to consider. Don’t rush into it, even if you are excited and energized. Then, schedule re-evaluations at specific points along the way. Mark your calendar to sit back and reflect whether your goals are being met or you need to readjust them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;at-the-start-of-a-venture&quot;&gt;At the Start of a Venture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are not one of the world’s “dreamers and schemers,” but many Golds have come up with brilliant business ideas and gotten rich from them. At your core, you are driven to be a responsible overseer of people and resources, and this makes you a cautious risk-taker. In your favor, you are not likely to be diverted by other opportunities. You will rely on tried-and-true methodology to move predictably from one milestone to the next.
Once in business, your first priority is establishing order. Systems and procedures are in place virtually from Day One. The sooner you can create predictability in your business, whether in sales, manufactured inventory or cash flow, the more comfortable you are.
Foreseeing and responding to changes in the marketplace will never be your forte, and handling unexpected crises is downright stressful to you. Make sure you have associates on board to handle emergencies and identify future trends and that might impact your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;approach-to-money--compensation&quot;&gt;Approach To Money &amp;amp; Compensation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finances-in-general&quot;&gt;Finances in general&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money is important to your sense of security. You are highly focused on saving and long-term planning, and fully in control of your cash flow at all times. You abhor the misuse of money and rarely go into debt or squander the assets you have. Your investments have to be well researched, backed by a solid track record and fully documented with concrete facts. As long as investments meet these criteria, you’ll invest directly in the market; but mutual funds are a popular option for Golds. You want your portfolio to be your passport to a worry-free future, and you are likely to achieve this goal early in life.
You have a limited tolerance for risk and volatility, favoring time-tested strategies. Fixed income instruments like bonds and GICs make you comfortable along with a portfolio of blue chip stocks. Meanwhile, you prefer working with well-established firms, insisting upon advisors who are organized, consistent and produce predictable results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;compensation--negotiating-style&quot;&gt;Compensation &amp;amp; Negotiating Style&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are a focused and tough negotiator, having researched what you’re worth well in advance. Gold/Blues can be prone to “bag person syndrome” - the fear that you will wind up penniless on the streets. Because you feel your security is on the line, you accept nothing less than everything there is to get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;job-search--your-strengths-and-potential-challenges&quot;&gt;Job Search – Your Strengths and Potential Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an interviewer whose style is close to your own, you will feel immediate rapport. However, if your interviewer is different, use the suggestions in parentheses below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In following your natural interviewing style, you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are calm and composed. (This can look like disinterest – make sure to speak more than you normally do, especially at first.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Present yourself as a capable and competent candidate. (You document your
experience well, in an easy-to-follow manner.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prefer written communications before face-to-face meetings. (Gather facts from all sources.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share few feelings with people. (Interviewers rely on their emotional response to you as a big part of their decision-making process. Prioritize building a personal rapport with such an interviewer by preparing answers to their emotion-based questions. Role play with a friend.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on the present. (Especially if interviewing for a senior level position, you will need to prepare a position on future planning. Research public statements about the company’s future direction prior to an interview.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are patient with the length of the search and the procedures you need to follow. (You’re likely to be the last one standing in a multiple-interview, trial-task type of job screening.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow through with all details; respect deadlines and commitments. (Interviewers respect that you send requested items, call to follow up and send thank-you notes. Your natural career exploration and strategizing strengths allow you to:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be calm and composed in an interview&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on the needs of the present&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide specific information, especially about the steps involved in completing projects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Present your background in a sequential, step-by-step way&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Think before replying&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show confidence in your ability to deal with bottom line issues In order to tone down your potential blind spots, you need to:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cushion your tendency to be abrupt; rehearse some areas of small talk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare questions to ask interviewer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare to talk about yourself on a personal level&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Express enthusiasm and be assertive about selling, not just stating, your accomplishments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do some thinking about a prospective company’s future direction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be willing to consider less obvious career opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here it listed out some possible jobs but I didn’t want to recreate all the formatting so I’ve included a link to it &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/pdf/Personality.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t necessarily agree with all of this but many things rang true which surprised me honestly.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/24/personality-test.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/24/personality-test.html</guid>
        
        <category>Job Search</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Light and Dark</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a fan of dark mode on sites, in development editors, and in the operating system too. Staring at a mostly white screen all day is exhausting and I like the way the content on screen emerges from the darkness with dark mode enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesg.blog/2024/11/24/dark-mode&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; from James G, I set about creating a light mode for this site. This is the reverse from what James had done as he started with a light mode but the the ideas are the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My :root to make this work currently looks like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;:root {
    color-scheme: light dark;
    --dark-background-color: rgb(26, 26, 26);
    --dark-foreground-color: rgb(32, 255, 188);
    --dark-link-color: rgb(25, 209, 255);
    --dark-text-color: rgb(240,240,240);

    --light-background-color: rgb(240,240,240);
    --light-foreground-color: rgb(0, 119, 83);    
    --light-link-color: rgb(1, 151, 189);
    --light-text-color: rgb(26, 26, 26);

    --line-color: rgba(211, 211, 211, 30%);
  }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;color-scheme&lt;/code&gt; term is required to respect the users setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the global variables set it’s just a matter of using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;light-dark()&lt;/code&gt; to set the appropriate colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;p, li, ul {
    color: light-dark(var(--light-text-color), var(--dark-text-color));
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still really prefer the dark mode version of the site, so check that out if you’re interested. It’s just a matter of toggling between light and dark in the browser settings. In Zen browser it’s in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;General &amp;gt; Language and Appearance&lt;/code&gt; which means I don’t even have to scroll in the settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which ever mode you prefer I hope you like what you see.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 14:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/23/light-and-dark.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/23/light-and-dark.html</guid>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
        <category>meta</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Now Update and Todo List</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve updated the &lt;a href=&quot;/now&quot;&gt;now&lt;/a&gt; page following recent events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I have a few items I’ve identified and included in the &lt;a href=&quot;/todo&quot;&gt;todo&lt;/a&gt; list for the site. I don’t believe I’ve linked to this previously so I thought I would do so now.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 17:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/22/now-update-and-todo-list.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/22/now-update-and-todo-list.html</guid>
        
        <category>now</category>
        
        <category>todo</category>
        
        <category>meta</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 12</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s week one of my &lt;a href=&quot;https://12weekyear.com/&quot;&gt;12 Week Year&lt;/a&gt; but it’s the 12th week of the year so I’m calling it week 12. This is meant to be forward looking to a week note for every week of the year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I updated my resume to showcase my experience, skills, and accomplishments as a Product Owner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Signed up at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nextjobtraining.com/&quot;&gt;NextJob&lt;/a&gt; to take advantage of that benefit from my previous employer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scheduled a meeting with a job coach for next week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/cshimes&quot;&gt;my LinkedIn profile&lt;/a&gt; and added a few people that I previously worked with in the past.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Originally planned to apply to a few jobs this week but have been saving them for next week and a better resume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Started documenting some specific projects I’ve had at work over the last few years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set resume/cv to appear in the main navigation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/21/weeknotes-week12.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/21/weeknotes-week12.html</guid>
        
        <category>Week Notes</category>
        
        <category>Week 12</category>
        
        <category>resume</category>
        
        <category>NextJob</category>
        
        <category>Product Owner</category>
        
        <category>Job Search</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting</title>
        <description>&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 16 years, 9 months and 12 days I’m unemployed. It’s upsetting and scary but also exciting in a way. That’s a long time for anyone to be doing something and it would be nice to do something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Already I’m looking for ways to use my time productively. I’ve always been somewhat dubious about self help books and influencers of that type. However, I have found a few things lately that I’m going to try. Looking to add some structure in the near term but maybe they’ll stick around and become habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like the idea of &lt;a href=&quot;https://doingweeknotes.com/&quot;&gt;Week Notes&lt;/a&gt;, a concept I’ve only been introduced to recently. The general idea is to post publicly (typically within an organization) what your team has worked on this week. Hopefully, making this information public gives other teams, leadership, etc., a better idea of what is going on. This of course is another silo breaking procedure but as activity more akin to a work journal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having sent status emails for years this seems like a nice way to add context to whatever dates may be out there. For example if there is something that comes up unexpectedly this could appear in the weeknote and help avoid future surprises. Of course this is not a replacement for other forms of communication but it may reach people outside of traditional channels. The public forum means not having to guess who should be included on the email chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly than that a team can celebrate a win every week. There are things worth celebrating all the time. Too often focus is on a larger deliverable when so many smaller victories happen every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What does that mean for me though?&lt;/em&gt; I’m going to be working toward my next job every week and documenting these efforts may help me. Having a bit of a self check-in weekly seems valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to the rest of the plan I’m starting today. I’m acting with intent over the next 12 weeks implementing a much more casual version of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://12weekyear.com/&quot;&gt;12 Week Year&lt;/a&gt; after watching this &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/5SPjd9Zu4-w?si=rjBU_E7WPI-ww1KC&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; by Zach Highley. I’ve made a few goals and I’m going to keep track of what I’m doing to try and accomplish them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help me keep track of my goals and my planned activities for the 12 weeks I’ve added a template already setup for this sort of thing on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.notion.so&quot;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re not famililar with Notion it started as a note taking app like Evernote. But it has turned into a suite of tools for project management, documentation, and collaboration. Random promotion of Notion aside I’ve got the system setup I just need to start the work.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 09:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/17/starting-weeknotes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/03/17/starting-weeknotes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Week Notes</category>
        
        <category>12 Week Year</category>
        
        <category>Notion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
